Pablo Gómez-Caldito | Senior SRE/Platform Engineer

Madrid, Spain | Email: pablo@caldito.me | Website: caldito | LinkedIn: caldito | LinkedI

ABOUT ME

I am a very self-taught, curious and proactive person. I love building tools, products and infrastructure using software. My work experience is mainly in SRE, increasing the reliability of online services and implementing the DevOps philosophy in organizations. I also release OSS projects, practice self-hosting in my homelab and have fun learning about InfoSec.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Java, Python, Go, Bash and Javascript.

Technologies: Linux, Ansible, Jenkins, Prometheus, InfluxDB, Grafana, Consul, AWS, GCP, Docker, Containers, Kubernetes, Git, Postgres and MySQL.

Industry Knowledge: Systems design, caching, CI/CD, IaC, CaC, SRE, Platform Engineering, DevOps philosophy, OSS, SDLC, agile methodologies, googling, AI-assisted programming, code review, reading others' code, pentesting, data protection, privacy and LLM deployments.

Soft Skills: Planning, adaptability, deep work, leadership, knowledge sharing, communication, writing and proactivity. **Languages:** English (C1) and Spanish (Native).

WORK EXPERIENCE

Adyen - Platform Engineer, Generative AI - Madrid, Spain (Hybrid)

Nov 2024 - Present

Building an in-house GenAl platform for developers to build their own LLM apps easily.

StreamSets (acquired by IBM) - Senior DevOps Engineer - Madrid, Spain (Remote)

Sep 2021 - Nov 2024

Leading technically a globally distributed team which focuses on the service reliability and enabling devs on the SDLC. Mainly working with Jenkins, Terraform, Bash, Ansible, Packer, Maven, AWS, GCP and K8s to manage Java and Scala services and products.

- Increased significantly every engineer's productivity by re-architecting the CI/CD system: Consolidated jobs into
 multipurpose-multibranch pipelines focused on DevEx and migrated them to a Jenkins managed as code in k8s.
- Ensured the reliability of the system and expanded the understanding of it by performing resilience testing
 against certain infrastructure outages and practicing disaster recovery scenarios.
- Enabled development teams to be autonomous during the SDLC and eliminated 50% of my team's workload with self-serviced Jenkins jobs and lots of documentation.
- Continuously improving team performance by implementing/improving processes: retrospectives, better code review, async communication, well written tasks and championing documentation.

Idealista - Platform Engineer - Madrid, Spain (Remote)

Feb 2020 - Sep 2021

Member of the Platform Team at the leading real estate portal of Southern Europe. Mainly working with: Ansible, Docker for testing, Jenkins, Consul, Prometheus, Grafana, and operating Java and PHP services deployed on a large on-premises network. Contributing on a regular basis to the company's OSS projects (available at github.com/idealista).

- Improved the observability of the infrastructure by designing, implementing and deploying a system that generates Grafana dashboards automatically using Python, Consul and Jsonnet.
- Accelerated 10x the creation of new infra and enabled other teams to take part in the whole SDLC by creating Cookiecutter templates for Ansible Roles and Playbooks. (github.com/idealista/cookiecutter-ansible-role)
- Increased the uptime of multiple acquired start-ups by refactoring their laC, creating or upgrading their whole monitoring and alerting stack, and adding CI/CD.

Kabel - DevOps Intern - Madrid, Spain (Office)

Oct 2019 - Feb 2020

Training on DevOps and cloud concepts: labs on Azure, Jenkins, Terraform, Ansible, Docker, K8s and OpenShift.

EDUCATION

Universidad Carlos III de Madrid - BSc Computer Science and Engineering - 7.48 / 10

Sep 2017 - Sep 2021

10/10 on Bachelor Thesis: "GitOps continuous deployment and management tool for k8s-based distributed systems".

Relevant Coursework: Programming, Data Structures and Algorithms, Discrete mathematics, Cryptography, Security Engineering, Operating Systems Design, Computer Networking, Distributed Systems and Mobile Device Security.

FEATURED SIDE-PROJECTS

- soup: GitOps operator for Kubernetes built with Go. (github.com/caldito/soup)
- mimcas: Multithreaded in-memory cache server built with Go. (github.com/caldito/mimcas)
- homelab: Self-hosting personal services in my own infrastructure for fun, learning and privacy. (talk)
- booklil: Built a second hand book marketplace MVP along with another 3 software engineers.

OTHER ACTIVITIES

Tech related: Hackathons, meetups and self-hosting.

Other interests: Volunteering, piano, reading, business, psychology, neuroscience and sports.